

Enrico Liscio

PhD researcher

Personal Details

Date of birth 20/09/1993

City Rijswijk, the Netherlands

e-mail e.liscio@tudelft.nl

Website enricoliscio.github.io

Personal Description

I truly believe that AI is an outstanding technology that can and must be used to help society progress. So that is what I set out to do: **research and develop** AI that can support us in better understanding each others. And I enjoy **divulging** it with videos for lay-people. Furthermore, as actor and former board member of an improvisational theatre association, I learned **organizational** and **communication** skills. Curiosity keeps me alive: **learning** something new brightens my days.

Working Experience

2020–present **PhD researcher**, *TU Delft*, Topic: personal values estimation in value-sensitive deliberation. Use NLP techniques to estimate individuals' personal values from text while deliberating about a topic of discussion.

2017–2020 **Technical Lead & Deep learning developer**, *Fizyr*, Delft RoboValley, development and implementation of state-of-the-art deep learning vision algorithms to solve challenges in automation and logistics industry.

2016–2017 **Graduate intern**, *Heemskerk Innovative Technology*, Delft RoboValley, development of autonomous robotic grasping of objects in cluttered environments.

Education

2015–2017 **Cum laude MSc**, *TU Delft, Final grade: 9/10.*Systems and Control (with the Robotics Institute Excellence Scholarship)

2012–2015 **Cum laude BSc**, *Università degli studi di Bologna*, *Final grade: 110L/110*. Automation Engineering

Publications

- 2022 **E. Liscio**, M. van der Meer, L. C. Siebert, C. M. Jonker, and P. K. Murukannaiah. What values should an agent align with? An Empirical Comparison of General and Context-Specific Values. *Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems*, 36(23):32.
- 2022 **E. Liscio**, A. E. Dondera, A Geadău, C. M. Jonker, and P. K. Murukannaiah. Cross-Domain Classification of Moral Values. In *Findings of NAACL '22*, *Seattle*, ACL, 2727-2745, [Reproducibility badge (top 3%)].
- 2022 **E. Liscio**, C. M. Jonker, and P. K. Murukannaiah. Identifying Context-Specific Values via Hybrid Intelligence: Poster Track. In *HHAI '22*, Amsterdam, IOS Press, 1-3, [Best poster award].
- 2022 M. van der Meer, **E. Liscio**, C. M. Jonker, Aske Plaat, Piek Vossen, and P. K. Murukannaiah. HyEnA: A Hybrid Method for Extracting Arguments from Opinions. In *HHAI '22*, Amsterdam, IOS Press, 1-15, [Best paper award].
- 2022 L. C. Siebert, E. Liscio, P. K. Murukannaiah, L. Kaptein, S. L. Spruit, J. van den Hoven, and C. M. Jonker. Estimating Value Preferences in a Hybrid Participatory System. In HHAI '22, Amsterdam, IOS Press, 1-14, [Best paper award finalist].
- 2021 E. Liscio, M. van der Meer, L. C. Siebert, C. M. Jonker, Niek Mouter, and P. K. Murukannaiah. Axies: Identifying and Evaluating Context-Specific Values. In AAMAS '21, Online, IFAAMAS, 799-808.
- 2021 **E. Liscio**, M. van der Meer, C. M. Jonker, and P. K. Murukannaiah. A Collaborative Platform for Identifying Context-Specific Values: Demonstration Track. In *AAMAS* '21, *Online*, IFAAMAS, 1773-1775.

Awards

- 2022 **TAILOR Scholarship**, Research visit scholarship, EU Horizon 2020.
- 2015–2017 **Excellence Scholarship**, *TU Delft Robotics scholarship*, Robotics institute.
- 2011–2014 **Excellence Scholarship**, *ENASARCO scholarship*, ENASARCO.

Invited Talks

2021 Estimating Context-Specific Values from Natural Language, *IIIA-CSIC*, Barcelona, [video].

Conferences

- 2022 **NAACL '22**, Lead author and presenter, Seattle.
- 2022 HHAI '22, Poster session, Amsterdam.
- 2021 **AAMAS '21**, Lead author and presenter, Online.
- 2020 BNAIC '20, Volunteer, Online.

Software Proficiency

Python	••••	SpaCy	••••	SQLite	••••
C++	••••	Keras/TF	••••	ROS	••••
Linux	••••	PyTorch	••••	L ATEX	••••

Languages

Italian Mothertongue

English IELTS Certificate - 7.5/9 Professionally fluent - C1 level

French Diplôme d'études en langue française (DELF) Can understand and speak - B1 level

Extra-Curricular Activities

2021–current **Volleyball**, *Inter Rijswijk*, player.

2015-current Improvisational theater, Delft Improv Group, improviser.

2016–2018 **Board member**, *Delft Improv Group*, chairman.

2016–2018 Volleyball/Basketball, D.S.V.V. Punch, player.

2016 Coach, TU Delft, introducing new students to the university.